Just like any other day,
I was taking photos for the literature club's homepage.
I found myself in front of Toyohashi Station.
I heard that Komari is at the city library...
Found her!
It looks like she's researching something.
Hey, Komari!
Wait a minute.
Huh?
Yeah, I got a good shot.
Hmm... What are you doing... all of a sudden...
Oh, it's for the literature club's homepage.
I wanted to capture natural shots of the club members and scenes around town.
Hmm... Nukumizu...
Sit down over there.
Huh?
Oh, what's up?
Wha—!
Why are you sitting next to me?
Hey, don't just move my bag without asking!
This table is pretty big, so it's hard to talk if we're sitting across from each other, right?
Even though this isn't a no-talking zone, we should still keep it down a bit.
Oh... I see.
That doesn't sound like something a peeping Tom would say.
A peeping Tom?
Is there really someone like that?
We should call the police.
Is someone from the Literature Club going to get arrested?
Yeah.
A peeping Tom...?
Are you talking about me by any chance?
Uh... yeah.
Make it up by dying.
Ha!
That's a terrible misunderstanding.
You could even call it slander.
Is that all you have to say for yourself?
Well, just hear me out.
When I pressed the shutter, you noticed something and turned around, didn't you, Komari?
So, Komari, you were aware of me the whole time.
Doesn't this fall outside the definition of a candid photo?
No, that's not right!
It's just a straightforward front-facing photo.
Taking photos without consent is considered spying.
I... won't accept any objections.
Then just agree to it here.
Look!
It's a great photo.
Uh... um... well...
My face is showing—
Oh, Komari, you turned out great in the photo, didn't you?
We need to share this charm with the whole world on our homepage!
Wha—
Uh... well... you mean... charm...?
This library is something we can be proud of anywhere.
We have to show everyone that we have a place like this in our hometown.
Huh... the library?
Library
I forgot to apply the filter, so I guess we can't use this photo.
Alright, let's delete this one and take another shot.
Die!
Why?
You can always add a filter later.
Show me your phone.
Oh, really? Is that so?
You can tweak it from the menu editing options.
Whoa! Nukumizu! You're too close!
Well... I guess there's no other choice, right?
I've got a privacy screen protector on my phone, so no one can peek.
This is the only way we can both see it together.
No one's going to look at your phone anyway.
Good grief.
Is Komari still there?
Huh?
Listen, when I'm on the train...
I'm playing a slightly questionable mobile game.
I can't let the kid sitting next to me see it, you know.
Hey, check out this icon. Want to give it a try?
Are you... not done tempting fate?
Why do you want me dead so badly?
Just leave me alone! Once you're done, just stay quiet!
You're getting in the way of my work.
Oh, by the way, what have you been researching this whole time?
I'm doing research for a novel.
I'm writing a story about a villainess, so I'm researching things like clothing and architecture.
Oh, so you're actually doing your research before you start writing.
Aren't you going to do any research?
I'm doing my research, but...
You're probably just using your research as an excuse to read manga and play games, aren't you?
How did you know?
You can tell just by reading your novel.
I haven't really researched anything, so my descriptions are all over the place, and I don't understand a thing about a woman's heart.
Oh, really? If you're going to say that much, why don't you teach me?
Uh... what exactly?
If you're saying I don't understand, then...
Komari, you can teach me. We've got plenty of time.
What?!
Um... well...
A woman's heart is... well, it's...
Huh? What are you talking about?
Since we're already at the library...
Could you teach me how to look up materials and stuff like that?
...sure.
Huh?
Die!
It's the second time! Die twice!
What do you mean by "second time"?
What's up? Why did you suddenly stand up?
Come with me... I'll show you how to use the library.
Hey, wait up!
Hold on!
Uh... um...
Library books are organized according to a specific system.
See... there you go.
There's a sticker with a number written on it next to the book.
Is it this one?
Even if I understand the classification, in my case...
I don't even know what I should be looking up in the first place...
No, it's the other way around!
People like you, who lack wisdom...
You need to search for the knowledge you need by looking through the categories.
Um...
So, what does that mean?
For example, what's the theme of that novel you're writing?
The pros and cons of redeveloping old town areas.
The theme is the weakening of community ties that comes with it.
Oh... that steamy rom-com... was it really about such a grand theme?
What I'm writing is a wholesome romantic comedy.
So, you're saying I should tone down the sexy scenes, right?
Uh... no, that's... you can keep it.
By the way... if it's about redevelopment...
Classification number 671, commercial policy and administration.
If there's a town you're using as a model, why not check out the local history section in the 090s?
Even just looking at the book titles could be helpful.
I see, a new perspective might give you some hints for your research.
Even if it doesn't directly become part of your story, it can add depth to your descriptions.
Your novel is set in a shopping district, right?
Maybe the commercial stores in 673 could be good material for your story.
Oh, I never thought about it that way.
Honestly, I don't really know how to use the library all that well.
Maybe they should teach that in school.
We actually covered that in class.
Oh...
Was it?
If you don't remember it, then it must have seamlessly become a part of you, like water.
In a way, haven't we achieved the purpose of the lesson?
Hmm... What's up, Komari?
Lately... you've been starting to remind me of Yanami.
Oh...
Seriously?
...You should really reflect on that.
Reflect on it.
That's scary...
If you spend too much time around Yanami, you'll start picking up her habits.
Be careful.
Um...
Pull yourself together, and you could always consider asking the librarian for advice.
That's... a last resort.
Why's that?
Talking to someone I don't know...
Impossible.
That's just you, Komari. Talking about whether you know the librarian or not...
Yeah, I guess there is.
R-right?
Well, if you think about it, everyone except family are basically strangers.
Maybe I've been too trusting of others all this time.
As long as you understand.
D-doubt everything!
I'm suddenly starting to feel scared.
Is it really okay for us to be using such a fancy library?
If we talk to the staff, do you think they'll set off a security alarm?
Don't worry... the book checkouts are self-service.
We can manage without having to talk to anyone... r-right?
Then that's a relief.
I guess that makes us library masters now.
There's one more thing.
You can reserve seats in this library.
Uh... Nukumizu, have you ever used it?
No, I haven't. Have you, Komari?
Uh... no, I haven't.
Um...
Is it really okay for someone like me to borrow it for free?
I think...
I understand...
I feel like there might be someone who needs it more.
It's a bit intimidating, isn't it?
But... today is different.
I'm going to be bold and... reserve a table!
Are you really going to do it? Right here, right now?
Uh... um...
The booth and lounge seats are...
It's not available.
How about the counter seats?
The side-by-side seats.
Uh... if you don't know them, sitting side by side...
It's kind of scary.
They might be enemies, after all.
Ah.
There's an empty booth over there.
Oh, it looks like a bench or something.
Oh... wow...
Let's sit over there.
Um...
This is the spot.
The window side is nice, Komari.
Whoa!
Are we going to sit together?
Well, this spot is meant for two people, right?
This was the only spot available.
Y-yeah... that's right...
Komari, are you sure you're done with your research?
Oh... I'll finish the rest at home.
Why are you looking at your phone, Nukumizu?
Oh, I was just thinking of checking through the photos for the homepage.
I need to decide which one to use.
Huh?
Isn't it just that one photo from earlier?
I heard you were made to take photos of Yanami too.
Hey, I think I did a pretty good job with this one, if I do say so myself.
Is it the Mizukami Building?
Yeah... Yanami's still eating like usual.
Yeah, she was eating.
She was practically inhaling it...
Wow... there are a ton of photos of Yanami.
She was eating so much that the photos kept coming out blurry.
I had to retake those photos so many times, you know.
Before I knew it, the canelés were all gone.
What a disaster that was.
What a waste of memory.
In comparison to that...
Is mine just one?
Oh, that's just my shaky hands.
Just one...
What's up?
Isn't my photo a bit blurry?
Look... look, right around here.
I did it on purpose.
Doesn't it actually give off a more stylish vibe?
Um... well...
There's something like... here...
It feels like there's something that looks like a face... showing up...
What?! Where?!
Could this be it?
There's definitely a sinister aura about it...
Ugh, th-that’s... my foot!
Don't zoom in!
Oh, is this not it?
Huh?
Lately, Komari...
Hasn't your skirt gotten a bit shorter?
Ouch!
Why did you kick me?!
Full body...?????
Wow, what's with that bizarre outburst?
Do you really not like this photo that much?
It's not that I don't like it, but...
Um, well...
What's up? If there's something on your mind, just say it.
So... that's why!
Maybe... a few more photos...
I guess I don't mind being photographed.
Hmm, I wonder what it could be?
Komari's acting all fidgety today.
She's kind of cute, though...
What's going on?
Oh.
I don't really get it, but...
This one photo should be enough.
You're not really comfortable with having your picture taken, are you, Komari?
N-no...
Um...
I...
If you really don't like this photo, I could blur it for you.
In fact, there's actually a demand for that kind of thing in some circles...
It's... being eaten by a fish...
Get on the chikuwa!
Hey, wait up!
Where are you going?
Komari abruptly stood up from her seat.
She quickly walked away from the scene.
She probably didn't like this, did she?
I think this photo captures Komari looking really cute.
She hurriedly left the scene.